Can't focus. My body is still puzzled about what to do.
Shuuchuu dekitenaina mada karada ga mayotteirunda
I'm trembling. I can't stop even if I try to control myself.
Furueteitanja kontoroorushitatte burerunda
Although neither sun nor moon are on my side,
Taiyou mo tsuki mo nanmo kanzen ni kocchi muiteinaiga
"I've no choice but to try,"
Yarushikanainda
Those were the words I muttered to myself.
Iikikaseruyouni sotto tsubuyaita
The odds aren't on my side, but running way'd be gutless.
Joukyou wa waruiga tada nigedasunja konjou nainaa
Even if I can't see the future, I'll just have to win it over with courage.
Tenbou wa naiga dokyou de kuria suru shika naiya
Need to keep distance from the target as I hold myself back.
Shoudou wa osaetamama taagetto to no kankaku sagure
All that's needed for victory is pride to win.
Hitsuyou na mon wa katsu puraido
Will we celebrate with the wine of victory
Ajiwau nowa shouri no bishu ka
Or'll we end up kissing their feet in defeat?
Soretomo haiboku no kujuu ka
There are two outcomes to everything.
Sou subete wa futatsu ni hitotsu
I want to control destiny.
Ayatsuritai unmei no ito
I need to seize the golden opportunity with my hands.
Zekkou no goorudentaimu kono te de tsukame
I'll finish it up with my best poker face,
Konshin no pookaafeisu kimete shikakeruyo
And drag them into a world of illusions.
Iryuujon no sekai e hikizurikonde
I'll find my way out of this endless pressure game,
Saigennai puresshaageemu sururito nukete
And leap over the borderline of honor.
Eikou no boodaarain tobikoeru tameni
How many? What'll I need to sacrifice to make it happen?
Haumenii? Dorekurai no daishou ga iru?
What is the one thing I don't want to let go?
Tebanashitakunai mon wa dore?
Hey, where the hell are you taking us?
Get in.
This is...
Military Headquarters?!
What does this mean?!
Hey.
You guys are filthy.
I wouldn't have dreamed the Homunculi's hideout was under Headquarters...
So it means that the army is also associated with them, not just the Führer President.
But I've got something good to tell you, too.
Really?! You really found my body?!
Yeah.
Although you told me,
"You're not my soul, so I can't come with you."
Great, so my body still exists!
Awesome! Awesome!
Okay!
This just means we're one step closer to our goal.
Hey, why do you still have that cat?
Oh, her?
Actually, inside of me, there's...
What?!
That midget?!
Brother! Stop being so loud!
Hurry and put your underwear on!
What are you guys doing?! Hurry up!
No!!!
Struggle of the Fool
Geez, why the hell did you have to bring her?
There was no other choice. She's injured.
Hey!
I'm leaving the rest to Wrath. Go in.
Wrath?
Wrath...
Führer President King Bradley?!
Colonel!
What the hell happened?
Quite a bit.
Sergeant Fuery was transferred to the South, Warrant Officer Falman to the North,
and Second Lieutenant Breda to the West.
And Lieutenant Hawkeye is going to be an assistant to the Führer President.
What the hell...
That's no more than taking hostages.
Have a seat.
Right now, it's just us and the Führer President in this room.
And he only has one weapon; a sword.
Yet, he's still confident he can beat all three of us?
Führer President!
You came to visit me in the hospital once, right?
I was completely fooled.
"Don't meddle in things.
Think of the entire army as your enemy."
That's what I told you.
You are all important to us.
You don't need to know about the minor details,
but behave until the time comes.
As long as you keep that promise, we won't harm you.
And when that time comes, what'll happen to the civilians who aren't "human sacrifices" like us?
I just told you. You don't need to know the minor details,
Fullmetal Alchemist.
"Fullmetal Alchemist", eh?
I chose to become a dog of the military in order to get my body back.
But the State Alchemist Institution itself was probably created to pick out these sacrifices.
If I'm going to be used by you guys again on top of that...
I quit my job as a State Alchemist!
Your proof of being a dog is covered in blood.
Whatever you guys are planning, I'll put an end to it.
I'll tell the other alchemists, and...
What was her name again?
Oh, that's right. Winry Rockbell.
Born in Resembool.
A childhood friend of yours
and someone who is practically family.
A skilled automail mechanic.
She currently works at Rush Valley,
and she's loved by her customers and friends.
She's a good, obedient girl.
Lay a finger on her and see what happens! People around her, too!
So, what are you going to do?
If you still want to quit, then I'll cut her down.
Excellent.
Excuse me...
We get the idea.
So, umm...
Like before, please let us continue to search for clues
for getting our bodies back while being under surveillance.
Please.
Very well.
As long as you don't interfere with our plan.
What will you do, Colonel Mustang?
You're not going to tell me that you plan to resign from the military too, are you?
Let's see... even if I became a dog of the military, I'd rather not become a loser.
Either way, because of my ambition, I won't be able to take off this uniform or get rid of this. For now, at least.
Very well.
You all may leave.
May I ask you one thing, sir?
What is it, Colonel?
Are you the one who killed Hughes?
No, it was not me.
Then who?
You said "one thing", did you not?
Please excuse me.
Oh. Wait a moment, Alphonse.
U-Umm... Is there something...
No, you may leave now.
That was so close!
A sword just went right over my head...
Oh yeah, Colonel.
Money. Lend me some change.
What's this all of a sudden?
Don't worry about it!
Man, this is all you got?
What are you, a thief?!
Oh well.
Later!
H-Hey!
Sorry, Colonel!
We'll report everything later!
What in the world are they up to?
Oh no, the Lieutenant!
Lieute-
Is something the matter, Colonel?
You don't look very well.
Can you blame me for feeling sick after seeing a musclehead when I was expecting to see a woman?
Colonel!
Lieutenant.
Is everything okay?
Oh, my apologies.
Lieutenant Hawkeye, just returning from the restroom, sir.
I accepted Major Armstrong's kindness and had him take my place for a short time.
Thank you, Major.
No problem at all.
You didn't run away?
Who's the one who told me
to never give up no matter what?
Don't regret later that you didn't run away, Lieutenant.
Like I will after all this time...
Hello?
Ed? What's with the sudden call?
Did you break your automail again?
No!
Hey, are you okay?
Are you doing well?
Anything new in your life?
You're not being stalked by anyone, are you?
Ed...
What is it?!
You're being creepy.
What did you say?!
I mean, it's rare enough for you to call, and it turns out you're worried about me?
Geez, there's something wrong here.
I bet it's going to snow tonight or something.
Hey! Do you have any idea how much I-
Hey, thanks.
I'm happy you called.
Thanks.
S-Sure.
So you're really okay, right?
Got it. Bye.
Good, she was fine...
It's your excitable nature that lets people take advantage of you.
Ling!
I told you, I'm Greed.
What the hell do you want?!
Your buddy asked me to give you this.
Ling did?
This is in Xing's language, huh...
What's it say?
I don't know. Can't read it.
He wants you to give it to the woman waiting for him.
Lan Fa-
You're not planning on following us and killing her, are you?
I'm not that low.
Besides, I don't like fighting girls.
I don't lie.
Later. Be sure to give it to her.
Hey, Ling!
I'm Greed.
Who the hell was that?
What reason did he have to start the civil war
when it would ruin this country?
Who is it?
Is someone up there?
You're injured.
Could you come down?
I'd like to know what's going on outside.
It's fine; the guard won't be coming again for a while.
I'm also a doctor. I'll tend your wounds.
An Ishbalan, huh?
That scar on your forehead...
Don't tell me... You're Scar?!
Who the hell are you?
What are you doing here?
Oh, God!
I'm...
I'm also an alchemist who assisted in the Ishbal Extermination!
She'll be fine. Nothing life-threatening.
She'll get better as long as she gets some rest.
Thank goodness.
"Thank goodness" my ass!
Giving me more patients by the day!
Both my bed and sofa are occupied!
Where the hell am I supposed to sleep, huh?!
I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
Besides, two patients in my house at once?!
Alphonse.
Lan Fan!
You shouldn't be up!
Is... Is the young master not with you?
I-It's fine. He's alive.
I have a message from him.
Lan Fan?
He says... He says he's obtained a philosopher's stone...
With this, our clan is...
That's right! I must return to my country immediately and tell my people!
Where is he? Where is the young master?
What? Why won't you speak?
Don't tell me something happened to him!
Answer me, Alphonse!
Where is the young master?!
How is your body feeling, Greed?
So you're Wrath.
I'm feeling fine.
Did you hear? This body belongs to a prince of Xing.
He wanted power that would help him become Emperor, and thus accepted me.
He's a really interesting guy.
Him and I once had a discussion on what it means to be a true king.
He said something like, "A King exists for his people. Without his people, there is no King."
What an idiot. He gave in to greed and lost everything.
Shut up!
Don't underestimate us humans!
That's how it is.
He's vigilantly watching for a chance to take over.
He's even planning on taking control of a monster?
How greedy can these humans get?
The Führer President is a Homunculus?!
It's always been my honor to fight for the weak citizens of this country.
Many people feel the same,
believe in the military, and sign up.
And yet, the military itself...
Why not resign?
With your personality, being a soldier will only hurt you.
Sir! This is wrong!
Are you going against military command?!
Whatever! Call for a replacement State Alchemist!
I ran from battle during Ishbal...
...because I thought what the army was doing was wrong.
But instead, I should have fought against it instead of running away.
Since then, not a day has passed that I didn't feel ashamed for bending my principles and fleeing.
And this time, if the army itself is the battlefield, how can I run away again?
What are you going to do now, Colonel?
I told the Führer President I wouldn't quit because I still have an ambition.
The fact the Führer President revealed he's a Homunculus means that even if he was to be defeated,
there's still someone else in the shadows.
I'm being tested.
Don't you think that's an honor?
You're being pretty calm about this.
I don't know if I'd say that.
It was the same when I fought that other Homunculus, Lust, but...
Although people accuse me of being a "weapon" and a "monster", when fighting against real monsters...
...I truly feel as though I'm nothing but an ordinary human.
I see.
So the young master took in the stone.
Sorry.
If only we had been able to stop him...
You don't need to apologize.
I am only mad at myself for not being able to fulfill my duty as a bodyguard.
So...
So the young master is still inside this Greed person, right?
Alphonse, I want a replacement arm. And quick.
But... it'll take some time...
Please introduce me to an automail mechanic! Please!
Okay.
I will soon.
But you have to get better before I do that.
Let's get you something to eat from Dr. Nox...
You can get up now?
Let's see... was your name May Chan?
May?!
What?!
As expected of the Yao Clan's watchdog.
And you're... the Chan Clan's successor.
Indeed.
I'm the 17th Princess of Xing, May Chan.
Wait... um...
If you're here in this country, it means... you're after immortality, as well.
I'll never let you and your clan have it!
You won't even be able to find it!
Hang on!
I don't really get it, but let's play nice!
Don't interfere with our country's affairs!
Don't underestimate me just because I'm injured.
Same to you!
What the hell are you two doing?!
Patients should be asleep in bed!
Don't interfere with our country's...
Hell if I care about your country's affairs, moron!
Geez!
Patients are patients, no matter what country they're in!
You're planning on messing up my house even more?
Hey...
You've heard about cases where unknown pathogens mysteriously appear in a doctor's house and kill everyone...
...right?!
This place really is a mess.
Doesn't he have anyone to clean for him?
Doctor, look.
Oh, so that's where it was.
Wait! Isn't this a picture of your family?!
It's my divorced wife and my son.
What?
I'm free to do whatever I want with my stuff!
Have a cup of coffee after this is all cleaned up.
I'm so glad you came!
Seriously, look at this.
I was at a loss about what to do.
Huh? Now that I think about it, I can use alchemy again.
Very nice work! This is all for the repairs.
But seriously, State Alchemists are something else.
On a totally different level from other alchemists.
The thing is, we asked nearby alchemists to help us this morning.
They were completely useless.
They came to the scene all full of themselves, and as soon as they were getting started, they told us it wasn't working.
In the morning...
That's around the time we were underground.
Mr. Alchemist!
Thanks!
Thanks.
Can I really believe what Envy said?
That those people are only made of energy, without a body or a soul...
Pull yourself together! Think about the future, not the past!
But at that time, other alchemists aside from Al and I were unable to use alchemy.
But that midget and Scar could.
What does this mean?
Alchemy that's different from ours...
If I could find out the secret behind it,
there may be a way to get Al's body back and fight against that geezer without using a philosopher's stone...
I have to return this to the Lieutenant.
Even if we part and meet again, I want to meet at this place.
巡り巡ってもまたここで逢いたい
Megurimeguttemo mata koko de aitai
Then we'll hold hands to ensure we'll never be separated again.
はぐれないようにこの手をつなぐんだ
Hagurenaiyouni kono te wo tsunagunda
We used to talk all night until the sun rose,
朝日が昇るまで語り合ったね
Asahi ga noboru made katariattane
And held hands till the sun went under the horizon.
夕陽が沈むまでつないだ手
Yuuhi ga shizumu made tsunaida te
Let's walk together like this forever, like light and shadow.
こうやって明日も明後日も共に歩もう光と影
Kouyatte asu mo asatte mo tomo ni ayumou hikari to kage
Right now I'm curious what you're holding inside
君 わ その 胸 に 何 を 抱え
Kimi wa sono mune ni nani wo kakae
And what kind of world you've been living in.
どんな 世界 に いたんだろう 今 思うよ
Donna sekai ni itandarou ima omouyo
I stand in the city, staring off into space with lonely eyes.
寂しげに見つめる街の中で
Samishige ni mitsumeru machi no naka de
I can't find warmth on my own.
温もりはひとりじゃ見つからなくて
Nukumori wa hitori ja mitsukaranakute
By meeting you, I realized
愛がこんなに強さになること
Ai ga konnani tsuyosa ni narukoto
How much strength love could give me.
知ったんだ　キミに出逢えてはじめて
Shittanda kimi ni deaete hajimete
Even if we part and meet again, I want to meet at this place.
巡り巡ってもまたここで逢いたい
Megurimeguttemo mata koko de aitai
Then we'll hold hands to ensure we'll never be separated again.
はぐれないようにこの手をつなぐんだ
Hagurenaiyouni kono te wo tsunagunda
I can't sleep by myself, 'cause I can't dream without you.
一人じゃ眠れない　夢は見れないから
Hitori ja nemurenai yume wa mirenaikara
So take me to a place where uncertainty can't reach us
どんな不安も届かないところへ
Donna fuan mo todokanai tokoro e
And let us bring light to the night sky with no stars.
星のない夜も照らし続けよう
Hoshi no yoru mo terashitsuzukeyou
I can't sleep by myself, 'cause I can't dream without you.
一人じゃ眠れない　夢は見れないから
Hitori ja nemurenai yume wa mirenaikara
So take me to a place where uncertainty can't reach us
どんな不安も届かないところへ
Donna fuan mo todokanai tokoro e
If I wish for a dream that can't be reached on my own,
一人 じゃ 叶わない 夢 を 描いたなら
Hitori ja kanawanai yume wo egaitanara
They made me help them.
With the two of us, we can make it come true.
君 と 二人 で 叶えに ゆくんだ
Kimi to futari de kanaeni yukunda
I created philosopher's stones and took the lives of many Ishbalans.
You and I are a pair; we can't achieve happiness without each other.
君 と 半分 一つ の 幸せ
Kimi to hanbun hitotsu no shiawase
And now, I'm on the verge of being forced to work on an experiment that would cause more deaths.
So...
So please, I'm begging you! Kill me!
Right here, right now!
I'm going to get back at them with death!
Right now, in my eyes, you appear as God...
You haven't told me everything about Ishbal yet!
What the hell did you bastards do there?!
Tell me everything, Marcoh!
Before my right hand destroys you!!!
Force. Never-ending violence.
The earth is drowned in blood.
The air is choked with the stench of burnt flesh.
Ishbal...
A detestable memory.
Next time, Fullmetal Alchemist:
Episode 30, The Ishvalan War of Extermination.
The Ishvalan War
of Extermination
I will recite the truth.
Although I'm the only one left.